# Bart McLeroy Mediator / Arbitrator

bart@mcleroyadr.com 214-763-2577

## **Profile**

Mediator / arbitrator with extensive experience resolving commercial disputes.

## **Alternative Dispute Resolution Experience**

#### **Financial Industry Regulatory Authority**

2015 - Present

Arbitrator for securities industry consumer / broker and broker / employer disputes.

# **Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts**

2007 - Present

Arbitrator for property valuation disputes between property owners and county appraisal districts.

### **Texas Department of Insurance**

2014 - 2019

Mediator for health insurance carrier / provider billing disputes.

# **Dallas County Courts**

2008 - 2010

Settlement week volunteer mediator for civil district courts.

#### SquareTrade, Inc.

2003 - 2006

Mediator for eBay buyer / seller disputes. Over 1,000 mediations conducted.

# **Real Estate Experience**

#### Jones Lang LaSalle

2003 - 2017

Provided outsourced real estate services for multinational clients. Job duties included consulting, sales, leasing, and portfolio / asset management. Worked with office, retail, industrial, land, and telecommunication sites.

#### **Cousins Properties**

1999 - 2003

Managed lease administration, forecasting, utility rebilling, \$25M in annual collections, and preparation of annual budget for 1.4 million square foot landmark commercial property.

### **Teaching Experience**

#### Collin College

2018 - Present

Professor of Real Estate

#### **Tarrant County College**

2005 - 2016

Adjunct Professor of Real Estate

# Education

**University of Applied Sciences** (Ludwigshafen, Germany) **University of Texas at Arlington** 

MBA, Logistics, 2018 M.S., Real Estate, 2004

University of Illinois

B.A., Economics, 1998

Professional Credentials: Texas Real Estate Broker License, Washington Real Estate Managing Broker License

ADR Training: See attached

# ADR Training (Current as of March 15, 2020)

# North Lake College (Irving, Texas)

Negotiation Skills for Dispute Resolution – 40 hours Mediation: A Comprehensive Introduction – 40 hours Introduction to Dispute Resolution – 40 hours Introduction to Law – 40 hours

# Texas Institute for Public Problem Solving

Conflict Prevention and Management – 4 hours

# National Academy of Arbitrators

Arbitration Workshop (2005) – 8 hours Arbitrator Training Workshop (2008) – 8 hours Arbitrator Training Workshop (2020) – 8 hours

# Association for Conflict Resolution – Dallas Chapter

Mediating & Negotiating Collection Cases – 1 hour

# University of Texas at Austin School of Law

International Arbitration – 8.25 hours

## University of Wisconsin – Madison

Mediation Techniques for Managing Conflict – 12 hours

### State Bar of Texas

Law of Arbitration – 2 hours

# North Seattle College

Alternative Dispute Resolution – 50 hours

# University of Texas at Arlington

Advanced ADR for Property Tax Appraisal – 8 hours

# **Texas Mediator Credentialing Association**

2017 Mediation Symposium – 6.25 hours

# Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

Arbitration Training – 6 hours

### Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

Dispute Resolution: Basic Arbitrator Training – 12 hours

Dispute Resolution: Expungement – 1.5 hours

# Universiteit Leiden

International Law in Action: The Arbitration of International Disputes – 10 hours

Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors
Acting as Advocate in Mediation – 1 hour
Arbitration - an Introduction – 1 hour

American Bar Association
Arbitration CLE – 7.5 hours
2019 Advanced Mediation Institute – 15 hours